# **Imara Paiz**

(510) 919-6384 | imarapaiz@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/imara-paiz-289666140 | https://bit.ly/2HwYeVH

# **Summary**

Application Programmer/Analyst, Report Developer, Data Analyst, Business Analyst with 15+ years of experience in higher education environments. Expertise writing SQL Queries, Oracle PL/SQL, PeopleSoft Query developer and Analyst with experience in Campus Solutions. Knows how to apply the Entity-Relationship data model techniques to create query reports, charts, dashboards and make them functional. Excellent team player and individual worker.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Reporting Tools: PS-Query, Excel (Pivot tables and VBA), SQL Queries, BI Publisher, Tableau, Knowledge of Crystal Reports. Knowledge of OBIEE. Knowledge of Oracle APEX.
- PeopleSoft Campus Solutions: PS-Query Manager, Connected Queries, Reporting Work Center updates.
- Databases: Oracle 11g, 10g, Oracle SQL Developer, MySQL, SQLite, SQL Alchemy, MongoDB, MS Access, Informix 4GL.
- Developer Environment: Eclipse IDE, PeopleSoft-PeopleTools, Visual Studio, Toad.
- Jira Project tracking tool
- Control Version tools: CVS, SVN, GitHub
- Programming Languages: Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Jupyter Notebook), Java, Oracle SQL, SQLPlus, PL/SQL, C, Pascal, Cobol.
- Web Development: JavaScript, jQuery, JSP, XML, XSL, CSS, HTML5, JSON, Bootstrap, Flask.
- Object Oriented Analysis and Design UML, Entity-Relationship Model -ERWin.
- Operating Systems: UNIX and vi editor, DOS Windows.
- MS-Office: Excel, Word, Power Point, MS-Project, Visio.
- Google Docs.

#### **PROFESSIONAL HISTORY**

# University of San Francisco USF | San Francisco, CA January 2019 – July 2019 SQL Report Developer

- Analysis of data to create queries in order to make data audit reports for the address, constituent, activities, alumni relations implemented in the Banner Advancement and Salesforce environments in the University Development office.
- Provided gueries to create data sources for Tableau reports of Addresses, Constituents, Donors, Alumni.
- Executed daily process of gift reconciliations and send reports to the officers in the Development Office. Wrote a guide to run this process. Trained co-worker on running this process.
- Created tables to the new design of Address and Activities relational data using Oracle Toad tool.
- Optimized queries and materialized views.

# University of California - Berkeley | Berkeley, CA May 1999 - June 2017 Peoplesoft Report Developer/ Data Conversion Analyst/ Business Analyst

- Requirement Gathering, Business Analysis, Data Analysis, Technical Specs, Design and Development of reports based in PSQUERY Manager for functional areas of: Graduate Division Financials, Campus Community, Advising, Admissions, Student Records.
- Added and Updated the Reporting Work Center Portal Objects, Pagelets and Navigation Collections in Campus Solutions.
- Trained functional users in the Graduate Division and Advising in PSQUERY tool to help them create their own reports.
- Defined views and expressions to improve the query joining among records.
- Data Conversion: Data Extract, Transforms and load staging tables/views for Bio-Demo student data. Data validation and verification.
- Used Excel to Component Interface utility to load data from Excel worksheet to Campus Solutions tables.

- Solved problems reported by users related to reports scheduling, execution and definition by the ticket system ServiceNow.
- Supported QA in User Acceptance Testing of reports requirements.
- Wrote reports in PS-Query, BI Publisher, Excel to Data Analysis, Cleansing, Profiling, Mapping and Data Conversion in the areas of: Student Records, Schedule of Classes, Financial Aid, Graduate Division, Campus Community, DB2 legacy reports.
- Helped to define and maintain data dictionary for reporting purposes.

#### Applications Programmer: Oracle PL/SQL Programmer

- Oracle Stored Procedures and web pages using Oracle Web Application Package for several reports such as:
   Bear Facts application for Staff and Students, Voting System, Final Exam Schedule, Emergency Address
   forms, Chemistry Web Pages, Advisors Code report pages. Student Degree Report Lists, Online Schedule of
   Classes, Electronic Grades, Midterm Grades, Student's addresses reports, Transcripts, Concurrent
   Enrollment reports.
- Programmed Oracle Packages including Stored Procedures, Functions, Cursors, Record Types, Tables,
  Views, Indexes, Triggers, Sequences, Exception Handling, SQL\*Loader. PL/SQL structure DECLARE, BEGIN,
  EXCEPTION, END, BULK processes, IF, CASE, FOR, WHILE, LOOP, Aggregated functions and Analytic such as
  OVER PARTITION, WITH PIVOT, LISTAGG and Regular Expressions.
- ER Data modeling and printable option for Online Schedule of Classes.
- Evaluated SQL Expert software tool for query optimization and tuning.
- Voting ASUC Elections web pages, load/update data in relational tables in Oracle PL/SQL.
- AP-Bears Faculty Curriculum pages in Oracle PL/SQL, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Bear Facts application GUI for Students using Java, XML, XSL.

# San Francisco State University | San Francisco, CA Dec 1997 - May 1999 System Administrator

- Defined the Setup and Definitions to manage the database used to control the access to the SFSU Library resources using OneCard system.
- OneCard database system maintenance, run daily updates, using Informix-4gl and UNIX commands.
- Programmed gueries reports for statistical purposes.
- Supported the user administration for the FRS System based on mainframe MVS/TSO.
- Programmed Oracle Reports 2.5 and 3.0 Developer/2000.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of California, Berkeley Extension | San Francisco, CA | April 2018

# Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualizations

Golden Gate University | San Francisco, CA | Dec 2004

#### MS in Web Design and Development

University of California, Berkeley Extension | San Francisco, CA | Dec 2000

# Certificate of Professional Sequence in Database Management Systems

Heriot-Watt University | Edinburgh, Scotland UK | Dec 1994

#### Diploma in Knowledge Based Systems

Universidad Nacional de Ingenieria | Managua, Nicaragua | Dec 1989

### **BS** in Computer Engineering

# **Other Courses**

Introduction to Data Sciences and Analytics (UC Berkeley Extension)

Business Intelligence with MS-SQL Server (UC Berkeley Extension)

Oracle9i AS: Develop Web Services (Oracle Corporation Education Center, Redwood City, CA)

Advanced PL/SQL (Oracle Corporation Education Center, Redwood City, CA)

Other Bilingual English/Spanish | Listen, Speak, Read and Write | US Citizen.